Floyd S. Fierman papers, ca. 1850-1997 (bulk: 1870 - 1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Western Texas' Jewish History
  - Fierman, Floyd (1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Eulogy for Fierman delivered Feb. 16, 1989 by Rabbi Kenneth Weiss.
  - Fierman, Floyd (2 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    "Service of Consecration" delivered by Fierman (Jan. 8, 1975) in Palm Springs, California.
    Photograph of Fierman and brief poem.
    Memorandum: Fierman to A. Chanin granting the Bloom Archives permission to reproduce under his signature any of the monographs that they hold (June 29, 1988).
  - Fierman, Floyd (3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Notes written by Fierman pertaining to his books.
    Letters - Charles W. Polzeroff to Fierman.
    Letters - Abraham Chanin to Fierman (Feb. 24, 1987).
    Article - "The Candelabrum and the Luminarios" (by Fierman).
    Article - "From Guten Tag to Buenos Dias...," (by Fierman).
    Various manuscripts by Fierman.
  - Fischbein. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Documentation from the Harding-Orr and McDaniel funeral homes regarding the funerals of J. H. Fischbein, M. Fischbein, G. R. Fischbein, L. Fischbein, and K. F. Taylor.
    Fierman's notes on the Fischbein family.
  - Forchheimer family. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Letter - from Paul Forchheimer to Fierman.
    Copy of section of "History of Brewster County" (by C.B. Casey; 1972).
    Article - "Forchheimer's, Landmark Department Store, Sells" (June 3, 1976).
  - Frank, Benny. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Freed, Sol. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Biography of Solomon Freed.
    Article - "Freed to Start New Lifestyle," El Paso Herald-Post (October 1, 1982).
  - Freiden, Jarvis P.: Notes and genealogy of the Freiden family (compiled by Fierman). (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Friedman, Max: Disability discharge certificate from army issued to M. Friedman (Jan. 11, 1918). (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Furman, Norton. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Handwritten genealogy and history of the Furman family (by Norton Furman).
    Letter and article written by N. Furman and sent to F.Fierman.
  - Galatzan Family (El Paso). (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Obituary for Joe Galatzan.
    Letter - M. Galatzan to A. Chanin (1989).
    Article - "The Galatzans of El Paso, Texas" (by M. Galatzan).
    Article - "Judge Galatzan Son of Immigrants" (Oct. 7, 1951).
  - Galveston Project. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Copy of selected section from Galveston (by D. McComb).
    Article -"The Galveston Movement" (by Henry Cohen).
    Passage on Rabbi Henry Cohen (1974).
    Article - "Spreading the Jewish Migrant in America..." (by L. Shpall).
  - Garbar family: Article - "Owner Default Puts Tenants in Water Fix," El Paso Herald-Post (July 26, 1984). (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Genealogies (El Paso and vicinity): Various genealogies from El Paso and the vicinity. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Giesberg, Morris. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Letters - Dick Giesberg to F.Fierman (1983).
    List of pioneers in which Morris Giesberg's name is found.
    Article - (Giesberg, Richard A.) "Mission to Ethiopia" (1982).
    Article - (Roos, Joseph) "Building Bridges of Understanding" (July 15, 1983).
    Article (in German) about Alexander Giesberg.
    Article - "Ex-Refusenik Discovers L.A. Advocate By Photo" (April, 25, 1983).
    Article - "The Plight of Ethiopia's Falasha Viewed First-Hand" (by Ruth Landis; April 1982).
  - Given family. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Program of the Given family reunion (July 1982; includes genealogies).
    Birth registration of Shoya [Given?] (written in German with English translation; 1882).
    Certificate of citizenship for Charles Given (May 14, 1895; includes photograph).
    Certificate of naturalization of Max Trogman (March 9, 1891).
    Article - "Transition List 'Given' Wrong Name," El Paso Times (December 18, 1982).
    Obituary for Deborah Given (February 22, 1983).
    Genealogy of the Given family.
    Letter - E.F. Cameron (attorney) to the beneficiaries of Morris Given.
    Letter - Maurice N. Eisendrath to "Friends" about cornerstone-laying (October 1950).
    F.Fierman's notes and genealogy of the Given family.
    "Given Family Tree" as organized by immediate families.
  - Goldfarb, Sol and Leona: Article - "Leona Goldfarb, 80, Still Offers Security" (October 16, 1980). (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Goldoft Family: Excerpt from Texas and Texans on Nathan and Maurice Goldoft. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Goldman, Milton, Fred, and Nathan. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Article - "PLO, not Mexicans, Responsible for Bigotry, El Paso Jews Decide" (Feb. 1, 1983).
    Article - "He's Not Fooled." (Jan. 16, 1984).
    Articles about N. and M. Goldman's ideas about stone-washed jeans (1980, 1982).
    Letter to friends about Jimmy Goldman's campaign (June 12, 1982).
    Invitation to the 50th wedding anniversary of Pauline and Milton Goldman (March 1982).
    Letter - Nathan Goldman to F.Fierman.
    Advertisement for Jim Goldman's campaign.
  - Goldstein, Abraham H.: Obituary for Abraham H. Goldstein (Nov. 22, 1933). (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Goodman family. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Article - "In the Beginning: The Jewish Community of El Paso, Texas" (1970).
    Article - "Joseph Hillel Goodman: Pioneer of the Early Southwest, 1895."
    F.Fierman's manuscript notes and genealogies on the Goodman family.
    Article - "....Jumbled Journal of a Canyon Crossing" (by H.M. Goodman, 1968).
    Letter - to F.Fierman from Goodman family members (Dec. 12, 1950).
    Clippings discussing the Goodman Building and the businesses of the Goodman family.
    Confirmation issued to Isidore Bernard Goodman (1912).
    Warranty deed issued to Joseph H. Goodman (Oct. 25, 1916).
    Unidentified correspondence written in the 1870s.
    Article and advertisement for the Goodman's insurance business.
  - Goodman, Ignatius. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Biography of Goodman by his daughter, Martha Katz (1979).
    F.Fierman's brief genealogy of the Goodman family.
  - Gordon, Frank and Leah: Brief history of Frank Gordon and Leah Strauss Gordon. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Gottlieb, Harry and Ray. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Document entitled "Gottlieb Family History."
    F.Fierman's notes on the Gottlieb family.
    Genealogy of the Gottlieb family.
    Eulogy for David Gottlieb.
    Letter regarding the immigration of Meyer Gottlieb's family (April-July 1939).
  - Harris, Polly: Two obituaries for Polly Harris ( El Paso Times; Dec. 7,13, 1987). (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Hart, Simeon. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    F. Fierman's notes on Simeon Hart (March 27, 1979).
    Article - "About Simeon Hart"(discusses Simeon's affiliation with the Catholic church).
    Order form by F.Fierman requests photocopies on Simeon Hart.
    U.S. Army muster roll indicating Simeon Hart's presence in the Mexican War (1847-48).
  - Heil, Levy, and Talpis. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Correspondence from Rabbi Eugene Levy to Fierman with regard to his family tree.
    Genealogy of the Heil family compiled by Rabbi Eugene Levy.
    Clipping - El Paso Times (1967; dedicated to the Union Fashion Store owned by Levy and Talpis, and originally founded by Louis Heil).
  - Heinemann, Sol and K. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Article - "El Paso Poet...." (about Katherine Heinemann's poetry reading at the Library of Congress, as well as her experiences in Washington D.C.).
    Letter - (June 12, 1982) from K. Heinemann to Fierman in regard to an article.
    Article written by the father of K. Heinemann which discusses Benjamin Disraeli.
    Heinemann family history (begins in 1826).
    Commentary by S. Heinemann (1982; discusses a compromise for abortion).
    Sol Heinemann's vita.
  - Himelstein, Philip: Brief biography of Philip and Peggy Don Himelstein. (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Holland family: Fierman's notes on the Holland Family (June 1980). (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Horwitz family. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Fierman's notes on the Horwitz family.
    Correspondence - Horwitz family to Fierman (about family history).
    Extensive genealogy of the Horwitz family compiled by Fierman.
    El Paso Community College newspaper (1988).
  - Jacobs, Albert Sidney: Notes on Albert Sidney Jacobs and other family members (Aug. 10, 1978). (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - The Jewish Voice of El Paso. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Joske Family. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Clippings - (1978; discusses family dry goods and clothing store, begun in San Antonio in 1873).
    Clipping - (1923; by Alexander Joske; discusses the strengths Jews and Christians).
    Letter - St. Joseph's Church to Mr. and Mrs. Schwartz (June 9, 1939).
  - Kahn family. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    Letter - Micheal Kahn to Fierman about his pamphlet "Beyond War" (1986).
    Pamphlet - "Beyond War: A New Way of Thinking" (1985).
  - Kahn, Simon. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    Kahn family tree.
    Clippings - (1961) about the history of Kahn's bakery business which began in 1913 in El Paso.
    Full page advertisement for Kahn's Bakery, Inc.
  - Kallison family: Letters - members of family to Fierman (1955-88; on history of El Paso Jews). (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Kandel, Ben: Editorial - (1983) El Paso Times (from Ben Kandel - about communism and the third world). (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Katz family. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    Katz family genealogy compiled by Fierman.
    Letter - Sugarman Bros. to B. Katz (1919; about value of Sugarman Bros. Store - El Paso).
    Letter from Shirley Nussbaum to Fierman (1972; on family history from 1899).
  - Kellen, Henry. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    Fierman's notes and genealogy of Katzenellenbogen family who immigrated to the United States from Lithuania in 1946 and changed name to Kellen.
    Excerpt - brief biography of several members of the Katzenellenbogen family.
    Clipping - (1982) Henry Kellen - survivor of the Nazi Holocaust.
  - Kern, Martin. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Brief genealogy of the Kern and Cohen family compiled by Fierman.
    Announcement - (1979) Martin Kern promoted to Executive VP, State National Bank.
    Biography of the Kern family.
    Letters from Martin Kern to Fierman (1983).
    Article - (1982; by David Kern) on divorce and child support.
    Advertisement for State National Bank (includes photo of Martin Kern; 1982).
    Announcement in the El Paso Times that Martin Kern was retiring (1985).
  - Kline, Arthur A. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Fierman's brief notes on Arthur Kline.
    Letter - Harold Sharfman to Fierman about envelope from store of Arthur A Kline (1982).
  - Kline, Joseph and Miriam: Joseph Kline's autobiography. (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Kohlberg, Ernst and Olga (Box 6, Folder 43)
    Letters by E. Kohlberg (1875-1877; trans. from German by W. Kohlberg; over 100 typed pages of letters as well as a brief biography of Ernst Kohlberg).
    Fierman's notes regarding Ernst Kohlberg.
    Clippings about E. Kohlberg's cigar business (1881-1924).
    Obituaries for Olga Kohlberg.
    Speech - Olga Kohlberg to the Women Pioneer's Luncheon (February 14, 1924).
    Program of the memorial service for Olga Kohlberg.
    Letter - J.B. Rawlings to Olga Kohlberg about her letter of resignation (Feb. 17, 1926).
    Genealogy of the Kohlberg family.
    Clipping - (1978) discusses the organizational involvement of Olga Kohlberg.
    Clipping - (1981) discusses Olga Kohlberg's organizational involvement.
  - Kohut, Rabbi: Letter - addressed to "Dear Sufferer" (1902). (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Kopiloitz, Lazar (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Krakauer, Adolph, Zork, and Moye. (Box 6, Folder 46)
    Addresses of Adolfo, Zork, and Moye Krakauer from Mexican directories (1908-9).
    Article - "Las Vallita Man is Witness in Salt War Killing of 1875" (about murder of Col. Crimmons by Judge Charles H. Howard and the witness of the killing, Adolph Krakauer).
    Letter from Arthur Obermayer to Fierman requesting information on family (1985).
    Letter from Leon Obermayer to Fierman provides information on family (Oct. 25, 1965).
    Fierman's notes and brief genealogy of the Krakauer family.
    Excerpt from Texas and Texans with history of Krakauer businesses.
    Clippings - ( El Paso Herald-Post) "Accidental Explosion Kills Robert Krakauer, Out Hunting" (1919; trans. of article by Fierman, and notes on R. Krakauer Memorial building; 1920-1).
    Article - "History of the Robert Krakauer Memorial Building" (by El Paso Executive Women's Council).
  - Krupp, Alvin and Janet. (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Krupp family. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    Notes from Fierman's interview with Frank Pickrell (April 14, 1964).
    Excerpt - "The Permian Basin: Petroleum Empire...." (by S.D. Myres).
    Excerpt - "Santa Rita" (by Martin W. Schwettmann; regarding business ventures of Haymon Krupp and Frank T. Pickrell).
    Letters - Fierman and the University of Texas (about Haymon Krupp; 1964).
    Article - "Historical Sketch of the Petroleum Development on University Lands" (Berte R. Haigh).
    Letter - Logan Wilson (Univ. of Texas) to Fierman with regard to the reconstruction of the Santa Rita No.1 rig for permanent display at the University (Nov. 4, 1958).
    Pamphlet which addresses the investment changes for the University's fiscal year 1977-78.
    Article - "The Myth of UT's Millions" (describes oil's influence on the Permanent Fund).
    George G. Matkin's remembrances of Hayman Krupp (Nov. 8, 1979).
    Article - ( New York Times) "The University of Texas Strikes Oil."
    Fierman's notes on Hayman Krupp.
    Legal document - Hayman Krupp vs. the United States of Mexico (1914).
    Financial analysis of The United, Inc. (1929-1950; compiled in 1980 by S.H. Lauterbach).
    Letter - Texas Secretary of State to Fierman about Hayman Krupp (Dec. 19, 1979).
    Letter from Haymon Krupp to Harry Spitz with regard to a trust agreement (May 30, 1941).
    Stock certificate issued to Haymon Krupp (1940).
    Contract - Haymon Krupp and the State National Bank of El Paso (May 19, 1941).
    "Who's Who Section," The Standard Blue Book- Texas (a brief entry on Haymon Krupp).
    Fierman's notes and genealogy of the Krupp family.
    Leon Krupp's reminiscence of being a volunteer in the Arizona National Guard.
    Will of Rebecca Goldstein Krupp.
    Letter - Elias Krupp to Carlyn Krupp about his interactions with Pancho Villa (Oct. 11, 1965).
    Obituary for Birdie Krupp Hewitt (daughter of Haymon Krupp; April 1979).
  - Krupp, Haymon (Box 6, Folder 48)
    Fierman's notes on the Krupp family (written on note cards).
    Article - "Pioneering For Deep Oil in Southwest Texas" (about his oil and land company).
    Article which addresses Haymon Krupp and his Santa Rita rig.
    Article - "Haymon Krupp, Economic Advisor" (written by Fierman).
    Clipping - (1936; New York Post) Krupp ridicules the charge of socialism against Pres. Roosevelt.
    Letter - (1983) from Paul Krupp to Fierman about two photographs of Krupp's family.
    Letter - (1980) to Fierman from "Eph" (discusses Eli, Paul, and Haymon Krupp).
    Biography and chronology of the life of Haymon Krupp (compiled by Alan Krupp).
    Article - "Haymon Krupp, Economic Adventurer in the Southwest" (by Fierman; 1981).
    Clipping - (1983) history of El Paso at the turn of the century.
    Clipping - (1981) discusses Fierman's article on Haymon Krupp; brief Description of Haymon Krupp.
    Brief biography of Harris Krupp (by his son, Paul Krupp).
    Biography on Harris Krupp taken from Texas and Texans.
    Excerpt - (p.116) Southwest Saga by McGaw (mentions the El Paso Hyman Krupp Company).
    Press release - announces that the original Santa Rita oil well will pump again (Nov. 20, 1958).
    Letter - Texas House of Representatives to Mrs. Rebecca Krupp (introduces a memorial resolution concerning Mr. Krupp; March 5, 1949).
    Letter - El Paso Community Chest (a resolution in honor of Mr. Krupp; April 1, 1949).
    Financial statement - contribution of funds to Mt. Sinai Congregation in honor of Haymon Krupp (1944).
    Resolution in memorial of Haymon Krupp Trustees of Mt. Sinai Congregation.
    Resolution - El Paso American Legion honors Haymon Krupp (1929).
    Resolutions commemorating the death of Haymon Krupp (1949).
    Letter - Rabbi Wendell Phillips to Rebecca Krupp (about death of Haymon Krupp).
    Letter - Alan Stone to Fierman requests advice for getting Krupp into El Paso Hall of Honor (1964).
    Statement by Hadassah in memorial of Haymon Krupp.
    Dedication speech for the Krupp Memorial Hall (Nov. 10, 1950; by Rabbi J. Roth).
    Description of the Haymon Krupp Memorial Chapel.
    Letter - Alan Stone to Fierman (1964, about 1936 article; in Yiddish).
    Articles which praise Haymon Krupp and provide biographical sketches of him.
    Document - "Resolution Concerning the Death of Hayman Krupp."
    Nomination of H. Krupp for election to the El Paso Hall of Honor (with vitae).
    Financial statement - (1938) Congregation B'nai Zion honors H. Krupp and awards him a cash gift.
    Obituaries for Haymon Krupp.
    Eulogy for Haymon Krupp.
  - Lapowski, Nathan. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    Obituary for Nathan Lapowski.
    Article - "Treasury Secretary..." (1961; discusses C.D. Dillon’s ties to Lapowski family).
    Description of the Nathan Lapowski family.
    Description of the Edmund Klein family.
    Letter - Jacob Marcus and William Nathan to Fierman.
    Speech by C.P. Fox about Errold Baum Lapowski.
    Certificate of Mrs. N. Lapowski from the United Daughters of the Confederacy (1920).
    Article - "Picks Will Be Revealed During Weekend," El Paso Times (Dec. 8, 1968).
  - Laskin/Talpis family. (Box 6, Folder 50)
    Letter - Lou Blumenthal to Fierman (April 12, 1972).
    Letter - Margaret Blumenthal to Fierman (Sept. 21, 1983).
    Genealogy and family history compiled by Fierman (June 2, 1980).
  - Lebuish family: Family tree of the Lebuish family. (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Lefkowitz, Carlyle Jerome: Certificate - honorable discharge of C. J. Lefkowitz from U.S. Navy (March 1946). (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Levenson, Sol. (Box 6, Folder 53)
    Genealogies for the Braunstien, Barnett, and Levenson families.
    Biography of Solomon Levenson (compiled by Fierman).
    Brief biography of Solomon Levenson.
  - Levitt, Leonard. (Box 6, Folder 54)
    Article - "Tribunal Meets to Hear Charges," The Prospector (July 15, 1982).
    Article - "Levitt Hearing Postponed," The Prospector (July 22, 1982).
    Article - "Regents Fire UTEP Professor," El Paso Times (Dec. 4, 1982).
    Fierman's notes with regard to the case against Leonard Levitt.
  - Levy, Abraham. (Box 6, Folder 55)
    Biography of Abraham Levy.
    Article -"A Cavalcade of Victoria and Victoria County..."
    Abraham Levy's application for U.S. citizenship (Jan. 21, 1849).
  - Levy, Myer: Letter to Fierman from Jeanne L. Gelber (Oct. 10, 1980). (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Lipson family. (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Manuscript which outlines some of the Lipson family history.
    Lipsonian Kinsmen Newsletter (October 1981).
  - Loewenstein, James and Juana: Obituaries for Juana Buchanan Loewenstein, with photo, Jan. 30, 1940. (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Mathias, Albert. (Box 6, Folder 59)
    Obituaries for Albert Mathias (1946).
    Genealogy of the Mathias family (compiled by Fierman).
    Miscellaneous articles about Albert Mathias.
  - Mayer family. (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Mayer, Rebecca Cohen. (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Moye, Max. (Box 6, Folder 62)
    F.Fierman's notes on E. Moye taken from the El Paso Herald-Post.
    Obituaries for Edward Moye (1933).
    Obituary for Max Moye (1933).
  - Nordwald family (Box 6, Folder 63)
    Article - "El Pasoans Sue to Get Back Death Mask" (Feb. 26, 1983).
    Letter - Leonardo M. Mayer to Fierman (July 5, 1982).
    Letter - Treasury Dept. to Fierman (July 26, 1967).
    Letter - American Consulate (Juarez, Chih. Mexico) to Fierman (June 6, 1967).
    Letter - to National Archives from Fierman (August 23, 1965).
    Letter - from Fierman to B. Nordwald, B. Mayer and S. Amberg (July 7, 1965).
    Letter - federal agencies to Fierman's request for information (1965).
    Fierman's notes and manuscript on the Nordwald family.
    Biography Otto Nordwald.
    Article - "Historia de la Cia. Industrial Nordwald S.A.," El Heraldo (April 2, 1950).
    Letter - Louis H. Scott to F.H. Seward (Asst. Secretary of State; July 9, 1877).
  - Nordwald family (Box 6, Folder 64)
    Report - death of Henry Nordwald (from Consulate in Chihuahua, Mexico; Jan. 15, 1924).
    Applications for registration and citizenship in America by Auguste Nordwald (1933).
    Certification of naturalization of Heineman Nordwald (March 3, 1870).
    Last will and testament of Henry Nordwald (Sept. 2, 1931; includes translation).
    Dispatch No. 23 (Sept. 12, 1879) - American consulate at Chihuahua to State Dept.
    Instruction No. 23 (October 7, 1879 and Sept. 26, 1879) - state to consulate, Chihuahua.
    Dispatch - consulate to state (Sept. 18, Oct. 3, 31, Nov. 7, 28, 1879).
    Order (trans.) of Gabriel Casavantes (Nov. 7, 1879; receipt for amount of forced loan).
    Proclamation (trans.) of Jesus Jose Casavantes (Oct. 31, 1879).
    Telegram (trans.) - Jesus Jose Casavantes to the President of the Republic (Nov. 2, 1879).
    Dispatch (trans.) - Jesus Jose Casavantes to the Secretary of Interior (Oct. 31, 1879).
    Orders signed by Gabriel Casavantes imposing a forced loan on Henry Nordwald.
    Affidavit of Otto Nordwald (July 6, 1935).
    Letters - F. Macmanos and Sons and H. Nordwald to the U.S. Minister (March 5, 1877).
    Letter - Louis H. Scott to John W. Foster (March 8, 1877).
    Case - the United States in the case of Macmanus and Nordwald (May 26, 1877).
    Letters - Louis H. Scott to State (March 5-July 9, 1877 and November 17, 1879).
    Letters - State to L.H. Scott (about forced loans on Americans in Mexico; October 7, 1879).
    Claim by Henry Norwald to the State of Texas, County of El Paso (July 6, 1935).
    Letter from Theo A.P. Brown to Mr. Nordwald.
  - Novick/Lerner family: Genealogy of the family compiled by Fierman. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Oppenheim, Ed: Conversation between Ed Oppenheim and Fierman (March 18, 1980). (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Paso Del Norte Jewish Historical Society: Bulletin - membership information, letters, and general announcements. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Phillipowski, Lyon (various spellings of surname). (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Picard/Bargman family. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pryzant family. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Letter - Nat and Doris Pryzant to Abe and Mildred Chanin (1992).
    Story by Sig Forman about Reb Itzhak (told to Forman by his grandfather).
  - Roberts, Frieda: Incomplete form (the Oral History Project; 1979) - based on interview with Frieda Roberts. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rosen family: Genealogy of the Rosen family compiled by Fierman. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rosenbaum, Louis. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Fierman's notes on Louis Rosenbaum.
    Letter - to F. and Edy Fierman from Dot and Bill (June 12, 1978).
    Article - "A Chauffeured Limousine to El Paso," L A. Times (May, 28, 1978).
  - Rosenfield family. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Letter - Leon Rosenfeld, Jr. to Fierman (1981-82).
    Genealogy of the Rosenfeld family (compiled by Fierman).
    Extensive genealogy of the Rosenfeld family (author unknown).
  - Roth, Rabbi Joseph M. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Greek Papyri Lights on Jewish History (New York; 1924).
    Biography of Joseph Roth (by Fierman).
    Article - "The Man Who Planted Vineyards" (by Hymer Rosen; a biography of Roth).
  - Rubin family. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Fierman's notes on Louis Rubin.
    Clipping - "$2 Million Plaza to Open...," El Paso Times (August 16, 1984).
  - Rueff, Gilbert. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Article - "Three Suspects Held in Juarez Kidnapping..." (transcription by Fierman).
    Brief Biography of Arturo Ducas (by Fierman; Ducas was Gilbert Rueff's uncle).
    Arturo Ducas of Juarez (author unknown).
  - Sabal family. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Fierman's notes on the Sabal family.